It's the battle of the single-leg glute
exercises. Which is best? In this video,
I'm going to roll through the top 20
single-leg glute exercises, and I'm
going to rank them according to their
effectiveness based on my opinion. Now,
before I dive into the exercises, I want
to mention two things. Number one, we
really don't have any longitudinal
research on this, so really it's
anyone's guess as to what really is
best. So, I'll be relying on sensations,
biomechanical rationale, and my
experience as a lifter and coach. And
then, the second thing I want to point
out is that I did not include B- stance
exercises. So, a lot of you out there
like B-stance squats, B-stance hip
thrusts, and especially B-stance RDLs,
but I omitted them because how do you
know how much loading you're putting on
one leg? You know, you set a PR, did you
really put more loading on the working
leg, or did you just use the stability
leg more? That being said, I do love
B-stance RDLs. A lot of you love them,
but this was really hard to do. In fact,
this video is going to piss off so many
of you because you're going to say, "I
love that exercise. Why was it number
two or number 12 or number 18?" The fact
of the matter is, most of these are
amazing glute exercises. In fact, I've
probably programmed 18 out of 20 in my
Booty by Bret programs. So, they're all
great glute exercises. Some of them are
more great than others. Coming in at
number 20, the single-leg glute bridge.
It's unstable. It's a tiny range of
motion. Even if you load it, you're just
doing a short squeeze position. You do
it and you're like, you feel gypped. You
want more range. You want to be doing a
hip thrust, not a glute bridge. For this
reason, comes in last. Coming in 19 is
the pistol squat. And I'll lump in the
single-leg box squat to this as well
because it's basically a variation of
the pistol squat. Now, the pistol squat
is arguably the best bodyweight
single-leg exercise in existence, but
it's a lot of quad. You know, the knee
has to go way out over the toe,
necessarily making it an amazing quad
exercise. So, [music] I'm not hating on
pistol squats. They're amazing, just not
so good for the glutes if you have the
option of using loading. Coming in at
number 18, the single-leg horizontal
back extension done off the glute-ham
developer. It's like the glute bridge.
It's all squeeze. You only feel it right
at the top. You don't feel any tension
at the bottom in the stretch position,
and you usually have to use momentum
because it's hard to get up there. It's
just too exaggerated. You don't grind
out the last rep. And something about
single-leg end-range hip extension
exercise, you kind of rotate as you
squeeze the glute at the top, throwing
off the stability. The torque angle
curve is too dramatic. You get nothing
at the bottom, everything at the top.
Therefore, it gets a very poor rank.
Next up, we have the sled push. Sled
pushes are amazing. They're so
functional. They're so awesome. They're
great for sprinters, great for
athletics, but there is no eccentric
phase, which could make it a good thing,
but it's also not always easy to
standardize. You better use the same
sled every time, the same surface, put
your hands in the same position. If you
go to a different gym, you have a
different surface, there could be more
friction, different sleds. Some sleds
don't allow for different hand
positions. But yeah, when you have a low
handle position and you're going all
out, it's a lot of glutes, but it's pure
concentric. Hard to replicate across
gyms. Therefore, it doesn't even crack
the top 15. Coming in 16, we have the
single-leg hack squat. I actually like
this exercise if you can lean forward a
bit, and there are ways to do it where
you're leaning forward, but the sled
itself is pretty heavy. Even using no
load is too challenging, and some people
experience knee pain even with a more
glute-dominant high foot placement. If
you like these, have at them, but there
are other machine movements like it that
are better, for example, the single-leg
leg press. Coming in at number 15, the
single-leg reverse V-squat. These are
like step-ups where you're angled
forward. They're actually amazing, but
they're actually too hard at the bottom,
so it's hard to even control it as you
descend. Typically, you see people
descend too fast, spring up. When it's
so hard at the bottom, you'll see people
kind of tilting the pelvis one way. You
do want the exercise hard in the stretch
position, but there's a sweet spot. And
some machines are better suited for the
single-leg version than others, making
it hard to replicate. And for this
reason, it does not crack the top 10.
Next up at 14, we have the curtsy lunge.
And some of you are going to say, "What?
I love curtsy lunges for glutes." So do
I. You get more stretch when you do
them, and then when that knee crosses
the midline, you get more stretch in the
upper glute max. But couple problems
with the curtsy lunge. Number one,
people never do it optimally. Some
people whip around, and you'll see their
shin angle move, but you tend to have to
go a little bit lighter. So, this might
place more burden on the upper glute max
at the expense of the lower glute max.
And we definitely want lower glute max,
so don't get me wrong, I love curtsy
lunges. You can actually curtsy almost
every single-leg movement if you wanted
to, but that's a general strategy to hit
more upper glute max as opposed to lower
glute max, and we want all the glute max
here. At 13, we have the single-leg 45°
hyper. So, it's definitely better than
the single-leg horizontal 45° hyper, and
I love the prisoner single-leg 45° hyper
arms overhead, but that's more of a
hamstring exercise. Some apparatuses let
you bend the knee a little bit, but
anyway you slice it, it never feels
stable. You always feel off a little
bit. I do love holding a dumbbell with
these, but that end-range squeeze, you
tend to externally rotate the hips as
you move into a full hip extension. So,
end-range single-leg movements sometimes
interfere with that natural rhythm.
Therefore, it does not crack the top 10.
Coming in at 12, the single-leg reverse
hyper. I actually love this exercise for
athletics. It's super explosive, and you
don't have that interference because
with open-chain movements like the
single-leg reverse hyper and the cable
kickback, you do have that ability to
turn the foot out or externally rotate
as you move into full hip extension. The
problem with this is you have to use a
lot of momentum. You're never going to
get that grindy last rep because it's
more of an explosive swinging movement.
And also, reverse hyper machines are
just rare. You don't see them in many
gyms, which is why it comes in at number
12. Number 11, we have the skater squat.
Now, if you just do a bodyweight skater
squat, that's a quad-dominant movement.
You're definitely limited by quad
strength, but if you brace, if you hold
on to something and reach back, now you
can make it very glute dominant. It's
almost like a step down. It's an amazing
glute exercise, but it's hard to gauge
your depth on these. What's the
difference between a glute-dominant
skater squat and a glute-dominant step
up? You just don't touch down, but do
you always reach the same depth? In my
experience as a coach, most people
don't. But it really is super effective,
and I hope a lot of you try it out
because chances are you're going to like
it. All right. Now, introducing the top
10. Coming in at number 10 is the
single-leg good morning, but not the
barbell variation. Barbell single-leg
good mornings would be brutal. It's so
unstable. What I'm talking about is the
Smith machine variation, and not with
the foot straight under the bar, with
the foot behind the bar a little bit.
When you do it this way, it is
absolutely brutal, and you don't do it
in a straight-leg fashion like a
stiff-leg deadlift. You do it in a
bent-leg fashion like a Romanian
deadlift. So, just treat it like an RDL
with the bar on your back and the bar in
front of the body a little bit. You're
going to love these, but I'm warning
you, these are very brutal, hard to
learn, but once you do, it's amazing.
Coming in at number nine, the pendulum
quadruped hip extension. Now, these are
done underneath a reverse hyper. You can
do them with a pure bent leg, or you can
do them more of a donkey kick style and
extend the knee, depending whether you
shift your body back or forwards
underneath the reverse hyper. These were
a staple in my training regimens all the
way up until around like 2012. My first
decade as a personal trainer, I
prescribed a ton of these because I
trained people my garage gym, and then
my first gym, Lift in Scottsdale, I
didn't have a lot of equipment, so we
did these round the clock. And the
people loved them, but they are brutal.
Most beginners start off with like a
25-lb plate, novices 50 lbs, and some of
my clients move up to 325-lb plates, but
it's so hard to stabilize. You feel it
in the core a ton, making it a good
functional exercise, but it would be
nice to have a little more natural
stability. If you do these, be sure to
brace on the unit, use a knee pad. I
never see these being done, but you can
see early in my career, I prescribed a
ton of these, and the people loved them.
Louie Simmons invented the reverse
hyper. I always wished I saw him using
these because I think these are even
better for glutes than reverse hypers,
but reverse hyper units are very rare,
so you won't see these being done very
often. Coming in at number eight, the
cable kickback. And some of you might be
upset at this. You're like, "I love
cable kickbacks." So do I. But I think
once you see the top seven, you'll agree
with my placement. What I love about
cable kickbacks, they match your
inherent strength curve. Meaning, when
you initiate the movement, you have a
little more torque on the hips, little
more hip extension torque requirements.
When you move into end-range hip
extension, the torque requirements
diminish. Well, you happen to be 2 and
1/2 times stronger at 90° of hip flexion
compared to 0° of hip flexion. Meaning,
your hips are stronger in the stretch
than in the squeeze because you have
more passive elastic force and more
leverage in the adductors in deep hip
flexion. When you move all the way into
the squeeze, now you're relying more on
active tension in the glute max. I love
them. I love all kickback variations. My
favorite is swoopy. You can also do
straight leg. You can do high pulley,
and you can do kneeling. They're all
amazing, but they're best done with
higher rep ranges. We mostly do sets of
12, but it's a pain in the butt having
to, you know, switch the ankle cuff or
wear two ankle cuffs, and then detach
yourself from the cable column and
reattach to the others. Let's be honest,
it's freaking annoying. The sets last
forever. So, for that reason, it's
number eight, but we do a ton of cable
kickbacks in my programs. They're
amazing, just not quite as amazing as
the next seven. Now, coming in number
seven will surprise some of you. It's
the machine kickback. But here's the
deal. Many of you will be watching this
going, "I hate the, you know, glute
kickback machine at my gym." And yeah,
when you find one that fits your body,
it's like gold. So, those of you who
have one at your gym that fits your body
well, you're like, "This machine is
priceless. I love it. I use it all the
time." But it's very rare to have that.
My favorite is the glute builder
kickback machine. It's so smooth. It's
so amazing. It moves you through a huge
arc because your foot's so out in front.
I queue push down, then back. It's
almost like doing a step down and then a
kickback. You're very stable, and there
are a lot of other good glute kickback
machines on the market. I remember the
old school Booty Blaster, which was well
suited mainly for taller people. But
what I like about the machines,
especially the selectorized ones, is it
it makes for a quicker setup. It's not
like the cable variation where it takes
forever. So, for these reasons, it got a
very good placement in the top seven.
Coming in at number six is the
single-leg hip thrust. Now, if this was
a bilateral list, the hip thrust would
be number one for me. It's my favorite
glute exercise. So, you might be
wondering, why is the single-leg version
not your number one single-leg glute
exercise? And throughout this video,
I've alluded to it. As you rise up and
move into full hip extension, there's a
natural hip external rotation component.
But, when you're doing single-leg, you
can't rotate externally. If you were
pushing on this leg, you'd rotate out
that way. In the single-leg version, you
move up and down. You don't get to
rotate out. When you do bilateral hip
thrust, you see a natural kind of
turning out as you squeeze right up to
the top. And for this reason, you never
see quite as high of glute EMG activity
with a single-leg variation than you do
the double-leg. Bilateral hip thrust
variations greatly outperform single-leg
hip thrust variations in glute EMG
activity, and it's the same hip range of
motion. So, that has to mean that
bilateral is better for the hip thrust
pattern. That being said, you know, you
can do single-leg hip thrust everywhere.
During the quarantine, people were
training from home. In my Booty by Bret
programs, we were doing three sets of 20
just with single-leg hip thrust off a
bench. They were brutal. Now, if you
have a dumbbell, you can just use a
dumbbell on the same-side leg. Put it
off kind of the corner. It works great.
Some people love using the Smith
machine. And again, as I said in the
beginning, you can do B-stance, too, to
make it even more stable. In fact, Smith
machine B-stance is freakishly stable.
But, when using B-stance, how do you
really know you're using the working
leg? Special mention goes to the
landmine single-leg hip thrust, which is
so awesome, but the setup is brutally
annoying. And finally, I love the dual
elevated single-leg hip thrust. It works
a lot of hamstrings. It brings the
hammies into it. But, at the bottom,
it's a lot of tension on the glutes in
the stretch position. Speaking of
probably second to the pistol squat in
terms of like the best single-leg
exercises for glutes if you're just
using body weight. But, I digress. Let's
move on to the top five. Coming in
number five is a single-leg leg press. I
freaking love single-leg leg presses for
glutes. Single-leg leg presses for quads
are awesome, too, if you put your foot
down low on the platform. The problem
with a glute dominant single-leg leg
press is you got to put your foot high
up on the platform, and you want the
back pad positioned up high. And when
you do it in this manner, it's a very
small range of motion for the hips. It's
essentially a lengthened partial. It's
so limited range. You're really not
moving the hip through much range of
motion. It's an awesome stretch position
exercise, and it's super stable. The
problem is I think you get a little more
glute growth when you're erecting the
torso and extending the thigh at the
same time. I don't have any evidence of
that. It's just a hunch, which is why
it's not numero uno. But, don't get me
wrong. I absolutely love single-leg leg
presses. Coming in number four is the
Bulgarian squat. A lot of you out there,
especially on social media, you know,
this would be your favorite single-leg
glute exercise. So, please don't get
upset for the number four placement.
They're a little hard to stabilize. If
you do barbell, if you do two dumbbells,
it's a little bit easier to stabilize,
but still some of the reps tend to be
problematic. I like it more when you
brace onto something, you use one
dumbbell, but you can get too strong for
that. I love Smith machine Bulgarian
split squats. I love plate-loaded. You
can use a deficit with these. They're so
amazing, and they really work you best
in a stretch position. You can lean
forward, make them more glute dominant.
They're such a great glute exercise.
But, the anecdotally, people's glutes
tend to get a little more sore from
lunge variations. So, I think lunges
work your glutes a little more. And
lunges don't make the number one spot
because they work too well. They make
your glutes too sore. You'll hear my
explanation in a second about that. So,
you might be thinking, well, why not
make them number one then? Because there
is an exercise that I think is even
better than the Bulgarian. And one other
thing with the Bulgarian is it's really
hard to not feel it in your quads. Even
when you do them in a very glute
dominant fashion, there's no way to
slice it. It's an amazing quad exercise.
And for that reason, some people don't
love it as much as they should. So, they
can be your number one glute exercise.
It's okay. We can agree to disagree. I
love it, but let's move on to number
three. Coming in in the top three,
number three is the reverse lunge. Now,
I like the barbell reverse lunge, but
it's unstable. You know, you can do
these standing on flat ground or in a
deficit. If you do do a deficit, I
recommend a slight deficit, not too
much, maybe just a few inches. But,
barbell is a little too unstable. You
tend to lose your balance. Same with
barbell walking lunges. You tend to use
your balance. But, barbell walking
lunges and and dumbbell walking lunges
are insane. They make your glutes more
sore than any movement out there. You
might be saying, then they're the best.
The reason why they make your glutes so
sore is because they work you so hard in
the stretch position, which is a clear
reason why they belong to be number one.
And I would agree with you if we all
trained glutes one day a week. So, if
you train legs one day a week or you
train glutes one day a week, do walking
lunges or reverse lunges. You'll be
recovered. They probably are the best in
terms of efficiency. The problem is
they're too good. They make your glutes
too sore. And therefore, if you train
your glutes three times a week, say
Monday, Wednesday, Friday, you hit them
hard on Monday or Wednesday, they're
definitely interfering with your next
glute workout. For this reason, I limit
the volume. I only have my clients do
one or two sets of these. Now, I will
tell you, I like braced reverse lunges.
I like flat reverse lunges more than the
deficit. I think going to parallel,
leaning forward, sitting back is the
best way to do them. But, I think a
slight deficit is fine, too, just not
too big of a deficit or you necessarily
make it more quad dominant. And when you
brace, you want to brace with the
same-side leg you're working and hold
onto the dumbbell in the contralateral
hand, the opposite hand, cuz that works
a little more glute. But, my favorite is
the Smith machine reverse lunge. And I
also like the plate-loaded reverse
lunge. I don't like the sliding reverse
lunges because how do you know you're
not using the sliding leg a lot? But, I
do want to mention, you know, some of my
clients get freakishly strong at these
reverse lunges on the Smith machine.
I've had Allegra, Ashley, and Carly all
hit 225 for 10, which is freaking
brutal. I've also had Joa do walking
barbell lunges with 225 lb for 12 steps,
so six with each leg. Phenomenal
exercise. And most of my followers are
women who train glutes three times a
week. Therefore, they are too good. So,
if you train glutes three times a week,
do these with less volume, one to two
hard sets. So, you might be thinking, if
these are number three, what are number
one and two? Well, I'm going to tell you
the number one and two and give you a
second to think about this. The
remaining two exercises are the
single-leg RDL and the step-up. Which
one would you pick for numero uno? This
was really hard to determine. Most of
you would pick the single-leg RDL at the
number one spot, but I put it as number
two. Now, if you did barbell single-leg
RDLs, they would not be very effective.
You're all over the place. It's really
hard to get the coordination down pat.
If you do dumbbells, it's a little bit
better. But, these are only really good
if you brace, in my opinion. And most
gyms only go up to 100 lb. Now, you
might be thinking, okay, I never do
single-leg RDLs with a 100-lb dumbbell.
Well, you can. You can get that strong,
especially if you're bracing, especially
if you just know that you can load these
up. My client Joa did 23 reps with the
100-lb dumbbell. The problem is, once
you get that strong, it can be a lot on
the sacrum, and you're limited by how
much you can hold on one hand. Now,
there's so many good single-leg RDL
variations. As I mentioned earlier, the
B-stance option is great. B-stance RDLs
are amazing, but you can also do them on
the Smith machine. You can do them off
like the Hammer Strength or like a
plate-loaded apparatus. My two favorite
single-leg RDL variations are actually
the adducted single-leg RDL, where you
put your leg off to the side. I feel
those so much in my glute, and you can
turn in a little bit, kind of curtsy if
you want. And the other is the
hip-supported single-leg RDL. I freaking
love those, especially as you reach out
a little bit, you can increase the
torque loading on the hips. But, some
people always feel these in the
hamstrings. As I mentioned earlier, it
can be a lot on the SI joint for some
people. I love them. They're so amazing,
but they did not reach the number one
spot because of the glute dominant
step-up. Another issue with the
single-leg RDL is that some women with
like smaller upper bodies, when they get
so strong, when they're start using a
100-lb dumbbell, they feel it in their
upper body a lot. It's tugging, it's
pulling, you know, they have smaller
upper bodies than men. So, men tend to
tolerate the greater loading better than
women, in my experience. And that should
be taken into account because most women
are stronger with the hinge pattern than
the squat pattern, and they can use more
loading. And it for some, it can
interfere with the effectiveness of the
movement. So, as you know by now, number
one is the step-up. And you might be
saying, what? Why would it be the
step-up? People butcher these left and
right. But, I'm of the strong opinion
that an exercise is to be judged by how
it's supposed to be done, not by how all
the newbies screw it up. So, yes, you go
watch people do step-ups. They plant off
the grounded leg and fling up. They use
a ton of momentum. They're all over the
place. They're wobbly, uncoordinated.
You can sometimes see people propel off
their bottom leg and then catch
themselves in a quarter squat position
at the top and finish off bilaterally,
which makes it a very poor glute
exercise. You can also do high step-ups,
which we love. High step-ups are very
quad dominant. I love the high step-up
for quads. But, when you do step-ups in
a glute dominant fashion, they're
amazing. Now, you need to be stable. If
you're trying to do barbell step-ups or
even double dumbbell step-ups, too
unstable. You need to be braced for
these, and you need to reach back, lean
forward, and really feel that glute
working on the way down. I made a post
on glute dominant step-ups. I think it
was late 2022, and I feel like that's
what sparked the step-up craze on social
media. It got so many views. It got so
many shares. And after that, all the
influencers started recommending them.
But, yeah, in my opinion, they are
number one when you perform it
correctly. You just go to parallel
depth, parallel thigh position, lean
forward, brace onto something, hold onto
a dumbbell, or you could put an ankle
weight on the back leg and brace with
two arms, or or you could use a cable
column. But, you are reaching back,
controlling yourself all the way down.
Think of it as a step down because right
before you touch down, that's when you
really want to be controlling the
weight, feeling the glute working in
that stretch position. Barely tap down.
Don't use the bottom leg for propulsion
at all. Tap down, come right back up. Do
it very intentional, very smooth and
controlled. And when done in this
manner, it is, in my opinion, the number
one glute exercise. Some of you might be
saying, well, it's the same exact
movement pattern as the Bulgarian split
squat and the reverse lunge, and it
makes your glutes less sore. Why would
it be number one? And that's exactly why
it's number one. Some of you have might
have heard me review the Plotkin 2023
study which compared squats to hip
thrust. They tied for glute growth. My
opinion on that is then hip thrust are
better cuz you can do way more volume of
hip thrust. So, when two exercises tie
for muscle growth, then the superior
movement is the one that beats you up
less, that you can do more volume of.
And in my experience, you can do glute
dominant step-ups 3 days per week,
unlike Bulgarians and reverse lunges.
Just like hip thrust, you can do hip
thrust 3 days a week, no problem, and
that's important for maximizing your
recoverable volume. Again, if you only
train glutes 1 day a week, I'd recommend
a reverse lunge. But, when you bend the
knee, the hamstring gets slackened.
Therefore, you don't use the hamstring
as much, you rely more on the glutes for
hip extension, also the adductors. So,
when you train the glutes in a stretched
position, you're also going to work a
lot of adductors. But, with the
single-leg RDL, you necessarily work a
little more hamstring. With a step-up,
you necessarily work the quad and
adductor a little more. If you're just
looking for a pure glute exercise that
doesn't work a lot of leg, then the
cable kickback would probably be your
optimal movement if you're just trying
to grow the glutes without growing the
legs. And one thing I do want to
mention, this study that everyone likes
to cite on social media, published by
Dr. Waldemar Nogueira, a Brazilian
researcher, excellent researcher, but he
did a review paper on exercise and glute
EMG, and he said the step-up is the
number one exercise that activates the
glutes the best. That is not true. Hip
thrust get you higher glute EMG, but the
step-up study that they referenced had
different normalization procedures. It's
kind of complicated, but basically, they
divided the EMG activity by an inferior
position, a bent- legged isometric hip
extension test, rather than the gold
standard, which is bent-leg hip
extension in full hip extension against
resistance applied to the manual thigh.
That's the gold standard. When you use
the same normalization procedures, hip
thrust get you way higher of glute EMG
activity. But, in the case of the
Plotkin study, we did see that squats
and hip thrust led to the same growth
because hip thrust probably produced
more active force, squats more passive
force, so it ended up being a tie. So,
EMG does not perfectly predict
hypertrophy. It probably predicts active
force real well, but not the stretch,
which is why you always want to include
both types of exercise into your glute
training programs. You want to work the
glutes in more of a stretch, and you
want to work them more in the squeeze.
And this list has it all. Lots of
stretch position movements, lots of
squeeze position movements. Now, what if
you love the top two? You love the
step-up, you love the Romanian, you
know, you love Bulgarians. What if you
wanted to combine the ultimate, you
know, single-leg exercise? Now, you
could do what I call the Romanian
Bulgarian. It's like half you Romanian
deadlift, half Bulgarian split squat.
It's more knee dominant than a Romanian,
it's more hip dominant than a Bulgarian.
So, it's kind of halfway in between. You
don't see this often, but this is a cool
variation you might want to try. And
another honorable mention is the
step-down movement off of the assisted
chin-up machines. I didn't include it in
my top 20 because most of you would
agree, you'd say, "Well, why not just do
a step-up?" But, I think if you wore a
weighted vest on those to hold you down
better and perform those in a glute
dominant fashion, and it was a really
good machine, I think those would be
amazing as well. They'd just be as good
as like single-leg leg presses, but it's
hard to get a really good machine for
that. But, you know what I'm talking
about, the assisted chin-up machines,
putting your foot on there and doing a
step-down. Because it's a little more
range than the leg press, and you can
make it just as glute dominant. But, we
don't carry around weighted vests, and
people who want to do chin-ups and dips
would just be pissed off at you for
hogging the machine. We've gotten super
creative over the years. Check out this
variation of a dual elevated loaded
single-leg hip thrust using our
rotisserie bar, our thruster pad bar
which swivels. This was an amazing glute
exercise, but who in the heck would ever
set this up? The point of me showing
this is you can get creative, you can
twist inwards, you can use dumbbells,
kettlebells, bands, chains, barbells,
Smith machines, plate-loaded devices,
machines, ipsilateral loading,
contralateral loading, do thrust and
bridge patterns, do hyper variations, do
squat, lunge, step-up, and leg press
patterns. They all work the glute max
very, very well. And the last thing I'm
going to say, you might be wondering,
"What about all the single-leg abduction
movements?" You know, gluteus hip
thrust, gluteus kickbacks, side-lying
hip raise, extra range single-leg hip
abductions, extra range fire hydrants. I
love these exercises, but those work the
upper glutes a little more, meaning the
gluteus medius and minimus. And then
some of them done in a transverse plane
work the upper glute max well, but not
so much the lower glute max, which is
why they were not included. That's a
wrap. I hope you guys enjoy the video.
Please like this video cuz I worked my
butt off on these, and they never get
that many views. YouTube consistently
does me dirty, that's why I don't post
that much on here. Please share it.
Please like it. Please leave a comment.
Spread the word because I don't think
there are many people out there with as
much experience with single-leg
movements than me. I've been lifting for
34 years, coaching for almost 30 years,
and extensively studying the
biomechanics of these movements for
around 15 years. I love glute training.
I love single-leg glute training, and I
hope you do, too. I'm Bret Contreras,
aka the glute guy.
Feel like it's my
favorite
my favorite
Feel like it's my